



Herndon, VA 20170



507-213-4872



zakyah@proton.me

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Full Stack Web Development

Career Foundry, Berlin Expected in December 2023

Google IT Support

Google January 2021

Bachelor of Commerce

Accounting Osmania University, Hyderabad, India April 2010

WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

- https://github.com/meetZak
- https://meetzak.github.io/portfo lio/
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/za karia-abdi-03414725b

SKILLS

- Front-End Skills: HTML, CSS
- Web and Application Servers
- JavaScript Libraries and Frameworks
- Azure Deployment
- Databases: Oracle, SQL Server, MongoDB
- TypeScript
- French

ZAKARIA ABDI

SUMMARY

User-minded Web Developer with a background in mental health. Able to translate skills in teaching and implementing evidence-based practices to effectively communicate with clients and create purposeful web solutions. Driven to grow expertise in website development by utilizing an analytical mindset and creativity to design responsive apps from start to finish.

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

Client-Side Programming & React, February 2023 - April 2023

- Created a non-relational database (MongoDB) of movements from various styles and to store user data.
- Built a REST-API with Node.js and Express, using Mongoose to interact with the database.
- Tested the API endpoints with Postman, wrote clean and concise documentation, deployed the API with https://render.com/.
- Created two single-page, responsive front-end applications, one using React (following MVC design patter) and the other Angular (with Angular Material). Users can create accounts, browse the library, and save their favorites. https://zaflix.netlify.app/login

React Native Mobile Chat App, July 2023- August 2023

- Programmed app in React Native and developed using Expo.
- Stored the chat conversation in Google Firestore Database.
- Let users pick and send images from the phone's image library.
- Allowed users to store images in Firebase Cloud Storage and read user's location data.

https://github.com/abuyusr/chat-app

EXPERIENCE

ASSISTANT MANAGER

Albryte Support Services | Sterling, VA | December 2020 - Current

- Leveraged database management system to track and report service hours, details of activities and progress on goals.
- Assisted in developing and maintaining user-friendly websites.
- Learn and adopt new technologies quickly and independently.

OFFICE COORDINATOR

Home Instead Senior Care | Manassas, VA | November 2020 - February 2021

- Organized workloads to streamline tasks and efficiently oversee day-to-day operations under tight deadlines.
- Supported internal team members with technical knowledge, operational support, and exemplary customer service.